- [Narrator] Mystery
Science Theater 3000,
show 412, reel one.
♪ In the
not-too-distant future ♪
♪ Next Sunday, A.D. ♪
♪ There was a guy named Joel ♪
♪ Not too different
from you or me ♪
♪ He worked at
Gizmonic Institute ♪
♪ Just another face
in a red jumpsuit ♪
♪ He did a good job
cleaning up the place ♪
♪ But his bosses
didn't like him ♪
♪ So they shot him into space ♪
♪ We'll send him cheesy movies ♪
♪ The worst we can
find, la la la ♪
♪ He'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪ And we'll monitor
his mind, la la la ♪
♪ Now keep in mind,
Joel can't control ♪
♪ Where the movies
begin or end, la la la ♪
♪ Because he used
those special parts ♪
♪ To make his robot friends ♪
♪ Robot roll call ♪
♪ Cambot ♪
- Pan Left.
♪ Gypsy ♪
- Hi, girl.
♪ Tom Servo ♪
- What a cool guy.
♪ Crow ♪
- He's a wisecracker.
♪ If you're wondering how
he eats and breathes ♪
♪ And other science
facts, la la la ♪
♪ Then repeat to yourself,
it's just a show ♪
♪ I should really just relax ♪
♪ For Mystery Science
Theater 3000 ♪
(doors whooshing)
- But you said that someday
I could watch the
movie with you guys!
- Gypsy, come on, you
know I need you to run
the higher functions of the
ship, that's why I created you.
- Yeah, you just
had me so I could do
all the work around here.
- Just a second, hi
everybody, welcome to
the Satellite of Love,
I'm Joel Robinson.
Gypsy and I were just
discussing the possibility
that maybe she might be included
in this week's experiment.
- Oh, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes!
- Okay, now Gypsy,
you know that Joel
created you and has
a wonderful plan
for your life, right?
- Yeah.
- And on the day he created you,
he gave you a special gift
that none of the other robots
on this ship share, right?
- You did?
- Right, and Joel wants
you to use that gift.
- He does?
- Richard Basehart.
- Don't patronize me, Joel!
- Okay.
Have you adjusted the
stabilizers on the ship?
- Done!
- Okay, have you told
the computer to give us
an uninterrupted
supply of oxygen?
- Roger dodger!
- Okay, have you
taken the heat shields
and pointed 'em up to the sun?
- Yep, twice!
- Okay, do you think you
could make witty remarks
all the way through
this week's movie?
- Yes, oh yes, oh
yes, oh yes, oh yes!
Sisters are doing
it for themselves.
- You're on, Gypsy!
- Oh, thank you, Mr.
Robinson, you won't be sorry!
- I can't believe it.
- Well, gotta go!
Don't start the
movie without me!
- Ixnay on the Ypsyjay!
- Come on, you
guys, take it easy.
You know, don't be
too hard on Gypsy,
we might have a
good time in there.
- Joel, you should've
stopped at two, Joel.
(upbeat music)
♪ Everyone's going to a movie ♪
- I don't know, Joel, I
still don't think it's
a very good idea to have
Gypsy watch the movie with us.
- Yeah, I mean, she's a fun gal,
she's got her own groove,
but to be quite frank,
I just don't think she's
down with the street.
- Well, I guess we'll find out.
Oops, looks like the
glimmer twins are calling.
- Good idea, Joel, get
Gypsy in on the fun.
(laughing)
(hammering)
Well, what I wanted
to say, Frank!
Anyway, Joel, I've been on
retreat most of this week.
Three days of silence,
prayer and simple food,
and I've left the invention
exchange up to Frank.
Yes, learning to relax,
learning to trust.
Let's see what he's
come up with, hmm?
Frank?
- Well, thank you.
As you all might remember,
Doctor Forrester and I
run a pretty hot
little daycare business
down here in Deep 13.
Doctor F handles
the business side
so I know all about
learning to trust.
(chuckling)
Whereas I handle the actually,
the actual hands-on work
of working with the
toddlers down here,
and yet I'm still stuck
doing all the lawn work.
Well, that's why I've
invented Lawn Baby.
Now our lawn can still have
that silken suburban sheen,
at the same time, I
can take little baby
for a leisurely stroll.
Wanna hand me that?
- Here you go, Frank.
(crying)
Frank!
You could've hurt baby Melvin!
Well, Joel, as you
can see, it's okay,
you can see this one may not
fly without a little more work.
So much for trusting.
(crying)
Oh, that's okay.
Why don't you go on with
your invention exchange?
- What a coincidence, you know,
we've also been getting into
the nesting instinct up here
on the Satellite of Love.
You know, it's becoming
popular for young parents
to begin molding and
shaping their children
from a very early age.
- Why, Joel, you're radiant!
- You're more
beautiful than ever.
- Thanks, you guys.
And we thought it would
be a really neat idea
for prenatal kids to get in on
some of the really cool music
that's going on right
now and also cash in
on some of those self
motivational tapes.
Enter the Wombmate.
You've got these headphones
that go over your stomach
like this and then
you play a tape.
Say you want the leader
of a future generation?
Play the theme music from
2001: A Space Odyssey,
"Thus Spoke Zarathustra."
- And if you want an infant
who can sell, sell, sell,
just pop in Brian Tracy's,
"Psychology of Achievement."
- You know, everyone
has abandonment issues.
- Sure.
- So play John Bradshaw's,
"Healing the Child Within,"
for you child within
your child within.
Hey, what's playing now, Joel?
- Oh, hmm, I don't
know, let me check.
It's Nazareth's "Hair
of the Dog" album.
- Oh, that's mine, how'd
that get in there anyway?
- I don't know, but I'm
sure glad I'm not pregnant.
- You're not, are you?
- No, of course not, silly.
What do you think, sirs?
- I'm having a little
problem hearing.
(crying)
I'm having a little
trouble hearing you.
Anyway, your experiment
this week is,
sad to say, the last
of the Hercules movies.
I can't even tell you the name
of the stiff that plays him
this time out.
Anyway, I've gotta go help
Frank with his little problem.
Why don't you go on ahead?
(alarm blaring)
(yelling)
(doors whooshing)
- [Gypsy] Movie's starting!
Come on, you guys,
Joel, Crow, Servo!
- [Joel] Hi, Gypsy.
- [Gypsy] Hercules
and the Captive Women,
well this sounds really fun.
- [Crow] Oh, Gypsy,
you are so naive.
- [Tom] Guys, I read
hieroglyphs, this
says that one time
this big lobster came
and attacked a lady
but Mr. Ed saved her.
(chuckling)
- Really?
- I think he's kidding, Gypsy.
- [Gypsy] Oh.
- [Tom] Man, I knew it,
Gypsy can't hang with us,
she's just isn't
down with the street!
- [Joel] Oh, come on, I
think she's doing fine.
- [Crow] Oh,
where's the sarcasm?
Where's the biting
acerbic commentary?
Where's the scimitar wit?
- Rapier, rapier.
- Yeah, whatever.
Come on, Gypsy, let's have it!
- Come on.
- Um, okay.
Look at that dumb
name, that's so stupid!
- [Crow] Oh brother!
- [Tom] Hey, General Music
Company, nothin' specific.
Slow or fast, that's
about all we have.
(chuckling)
(awe-inspiring music)
(vocalizing)
- [Joel] Hey, look,
a chili pizza.
Who's hungry for chili pizza?
- [Gypsy] I am, that
sounds delicious.
- [Tom] Gypsy, I weep for you.
(awe-inspiring music)
Cottafani candy.
- Bonanza!
- This is ancient Greece.
- [Tom] And if that map
burns, it'll be a Greece fire.
(chuckling)
- Good one.
- [Narrator] The
King of Thebes was--
- [Joel] Was what,
what happened to him?
- [Tom] Oh forget it,
just enjoy, friends.
- [Narrator] Hercules
and his son Hylas
were loyal to this brave ruler.
- I'm the King of Thebes!
- [Gypsy] Hey,
hey, stop fighting,
everybody stop fighting!
- It's okay, Gypsy,
it's just a movie.
- [Crow] The service here is
great, even during a fight!
- [Narrator] Good-natured
brawling was a necessity.
- [Crow] Good natured?
- [Narrator] To keep the
young warriors fit and strong.
The wars were always present.
(yelling)
- [Tom] Boy, it's busier
in here than usual.
- [Crow] I hope
that's not Hercules.
Oh no, it is!
- [Hercules] That's
enough now, boys.
- [Tom] You got a
phone I can use?
- Come on.
- Oh they're bathing together,
that's weird.
- Not in Greece it isn't.
- [Gypsy] Oh, they've
got a fun friend!
- [Crow] And we've got
a junior buffalo shot.
(chuckling)
(vocalizing)
- [Timoteo] You too!
- [Narrator] History
tells us of the war--
- [Joel] And now
I'm going to too.
- [Narrator] Tell us of an
era when the unforeseen perils
of the mystical unknown
were always lurking.
This is one of those legends.
(wind blowing)
- [Gypsy] Hey, get this, they're
steam cleaning the horses!
- All right, good one!
- Hey!
- You've got it.
- Yeah.
- Look there, the sun!
- [Tom] Yeah, what's
it doing up there?
(ominous music)
- [Man] Stop, stop
where are you going?
All Greece is bleeding,
pity our poor country!
Flee for your lives!
- What are you trying to
say, where do you come from?
- [Crow] Who's your daddy?
- [Man] Not from wounds, but
is falling from the heavens
with flames and poisonous
serpents, monstrous powers--
- [Joel] Sounds pretty bad.
- [Man] In all our cities,
the people are fleeing before
the deadly shadow which is
bringing night without end!
Can't you see the rain
of blood and fire?
- He's long winded.
- Yeah.
- The cities of Greece.
- Hermie.
- From the heavens!
- Pink and red.
- That's great,
really good audition
piece, thank you.
- [Crow] Very nice, very nice.
(ominous music)
- [Tom] It's like
roller bubbles.
That must be that
Moses character
I've heard him talk
about so much lately.
- [Joel] Mmm.
- [Crow] He's not
heavy, he's my brother.
(ominous music)
- [Tom] Ooh, sundogs.
- Where did he go to,
what did he leave?
- I don't know, it must be
a sign from the heavens.
Only the prophet Tiresias
can tell us what it means.
- He's in Thebes, come on.
- [Joel] Whack today,
we weren't supposed
to take the brown acid.
- [Gypsy] I don't get it.
- [Tom] Neither do we, Gypsy.
(vocalizing)
♪ How do you solve a
problem like Maria ♪
- [Crow] I think it's a
take back the night march.
- [Joel] I think
we're being followed.
Just act natural.
- [Tom] Hope he
can make that hill.
(screeching)
- [Tiresias] The
gods have spoken.
- [Tom] But I couldn't
understand them.
- With lightning, with the
winds they have spoken.
But not by menacing
or by punishing
but through their life-giving
powers they have spoken.
- What have they
said, oh wise one?
- [Crow] They said,
"Will the owner of a
"white Toyota Camry please--"
- Who can say?
A peril hangs over all our land.
A peril from afar.
- [Joel] In fact, apparel
is half off this week.
- Who would dare
attack the Greeks?
- Evil is upon us.
Forces of unbelievable horror.
- Horror.
- To the people.
- Through the straights from
which no vessel has returned.
- [Crow] Over here.
- [Tiresias] Across
unknown seas.
- [Gypsy] You guys,
you know, this movie
isn't really that good.
- Yeah.
- [Tom] Yes.
Right, that's true.
That's great, gramps.
Start the car,
I'll be right out.
- [Gypsy] Um, you
guys, I just remembered
I've got a billion things to do.
- [Joel] What, you
can't leave now,
you wanted to sit through
the whole experiment.
- [Gypsy] But, that
was before I knew,
and then there
were these things.
And now I have to go do them.
- [Crow] Well, if you
can't stand the heat.
- [Joel] That's okay, Gypsy,
run along, that's really fine.
- [Tom] Go on.
- The city councilors to ever
manage to reach an accord.
- Thanks to the guards I
alone commanded my kingdom.
Androcles is right, we should--
- [Joel] She did her best,
I don't want you guys--
- [Crow] Shh, Joel,
watch the movie!
- [Joel] Please,
it's a bad movie.
- [Crow] I'll just sit.
(laughing)
- [Tom] Shut up, it's not funny.
- Better to divide
ourselves, one post attacks
the other defends.
- Dear brothers, we didn't
come here to bring up
the things which divide us.
We must unite against the
enemy that menaces us.
Would you perhaps prefer
that we wait here helplessly
for the moment when the
enemy will decide to attack,
to destroy all of our cities?
- [Joel] He's got
Earl Campbell thighs.
- My soldiers are invincible
and my navy big enough
to transport them.
(gasping)
(stammering)
- [Crow] Return to my seat.
- Watch, Androcles, look
at the outlines of Greece
over on the map, and within
the confines of my own land.
I swear by all the gods--
- Gimme that.
- That no enemy will ever pass.
- Look out, he's drunk!
- Duck!
(boinging)
- Doesn't impress me.
- Look here!
(boinging)
(laughing)
- If you think
I'd be impressed--
- [Joel] Ah, excuse
me, you're on fire.
(blowing)
- Even a king can
court misfortune if
he's too intriguing.
- [Crow] Hey, Dr. Zira!
- The tribute money
from the last war
is still waiting to be paid.
- If you think to fill
your coffers with my gold
because we're now
forced to be allies...
No!
- Okay, yes!
I changed my mind.
- I must go alone.
- They lost me.
Way back there.
- Abandoning my kingdom
to defend all of yours?
- Oh!
- Look at that guy!
- See to it that nobody
sits upon your throne
during your absence.
(yelling)
- [Crow] Yuck, do you mind?
- [Tom] I think it would
go something like this.
- [Joel] If you don't
mind, I kinda need to do
some squats right now.
- [Crow] Take this
out to the garage.
Wonder what his max is?
- Your throne shall be rebuilt
the day you return, Androcles.
- [Tom] Uh, thanks, I think.
- What a waste of a fine throne.
It was carved especially
for me in Tyros.
- [Crow] Now it's garbage.
- We shall sculpt one
far more beautiful
to celebrate your homecoming.
- [Tom] But I can't go
to homecoming with you.
(upbeat music)
(adventurous music)
It's a Carnival cruise ship.
(gentle instrumental music)
(groaning)
- [Crow] I'm almost done,
hey, bring me a magazine.
- [Joel] You know what, Tony?
If we all work together
we could beat Harvard!
- Do you think
he'll be very mad?
- Difficult to say
before he wakes up.
No matter, we're
miles from shore.
- When papa finds out I put a
sleeping powder in his wine...
- Hey, he's coming around.
- You take over, if he
finds out that I'm here
on board we're all done for!
- [Tom] Well if he finds
out you dressed him
in a mini skirt you'll be
in even bigger trouble.
- [Timoteo] Wait,
I'll come with ya!
- No, you stay here.
- [Crow] Oh, sure, boss
around the little guy.
(vocalizing)
- [Joel] Down the hatch.
Ooh, I didn't see that.
(groaning)
- [Crow] Whoa, did I
toss a throne last night?
- [Joel] Oh, I must've
overslept, Hercules style.
- [Tom] Anybody know where
to get breakfast around here?
(chewing)
(burping)
- [Joel] Why you son of a...
(chuckling)
- Lovely day, isn't it?
- Yep.
(chuckling nervously)
- [Crow] Don't hurt me.
- [Tom] That's nice, huh?
- How long have we been at sea?
- Since sun up.
- [Tom] Oh, sun up,
good, yes, that's nice.
I wanna go home, I wanna
go home to the farm,
I wanna go home!
- Where's your fleet?
- At the bottom of my leg.
- Well...
- And where are your warriors?
- [Joel] I ate 'em?
- It's because of that
I brought you with us.
- I understand, I understand.
- [Tom] I'm a rational
man, I'm a rational man.
- And is this your crew?
- They're my little brother's
friends, there's
really nothing much.
- [Crow] All right, I love
it, we're gonna have fun.
- Fine company.
- It's the best I could find.
- But I thought you
were the King of Thebes.
(scoffing)
- I wish!
- I fought against the
soothsayers, the senators,
the commanders of the army.
Aren't you always saying
that democracy is--
- Never mind, never mind.
Any way, I was right to
smash the throne, wasn't I?
- [Joel] Oh, lay that one on me.
- [Tom] Ooh!
- Now,
how do you intend
to beat the enemy?
(yelling)
Oh, I forgot.
- Hey, Hercules, put him down!
- We've got Timoteo.
- No need for irony.
An enemy we've never seen
is twice as powerful.
We now have to find
out who this enemy is.
- [Joel] All done?
- [Androcles] From what
unknown land he threatens us.
How strong he is.
- Yeah, sure.
- How great are his armies?
(groaning)
From where does he
intend to attack us?
- [Tom] Look, wake
me up when you get
to the plot point, okay?
Good night.
- Hercules, what are you doing?
- I'm sleepy.
- Aw, that's our Herc!
(vocalizing)
That's, oh that funny,
cumbersome clown.
- I'd prefer for
him to hit somebody.
- [Crow] Well, whatever tugs
at your bobber, little fella.
- [Joel] Steve Austin.
- [Tom] Meanwhile, in
the very same scene...
(vocalizing)
- [Crow] Hey, come back
here with my dinner roll!
- [Tom] You weren't
gonna eat it anyway!
- I was too!
- I seem to remember
my fruit cup being missing.
- You took my brownie
the other day!
- I didn't take your brownie.
- [Tom] I buttered it,
you didn't even butter it!
- [Joel] Push him over,
push him overboard.
- [Tom] Give you another
dinner roll some other time.
No, I'm afraid it's mine.
Dinner roll.
- Yeah?
- Dinner roll you.
Hey, who left the
rudder on land?
- [Tom] Oh jeez, I got a
backup on table 10 and,
oh, good morning, sir.
Frosted Lucky Charms, sir.
- Wake up!
I brought some food.
(groaning)
- [Crow] I went home with you?
- Oh, it's impossible.
I've hid down here in
this hole six long days.
I've gotten seasick
in the bargain.
I'm going up.
- No!
- No you don't!
- [Tom] Buffalo shot
to yourself there!
- We're lost if Hercules
finds you on board.
The only thing he's been
asking all these days
is whether you're at
home safe and sound.
- Did you tell him I was?
- Don't be silly.
- What else did he say?
- Nothing, mostly he sleeps.
When he doesn't sleep he fishes.
- Fishes?
- You know, line, hook, worm?
- None.
- [Crow] Good night
now, that's our time.
- [Tom] Join us in the world
of snails and adventure
as we board the Golden Hind.
(adventurous music)
- [Joel] Oh great,
a Marmaduke ship.
(barking)
- [Tom] Maybe if the
pulled up the anchor
the plot would move a little.
- [Crow] Oh Harry, taking
pictures of nothing again?
(gentle instrumental music)
- [Tom] Oh dear lord,
the canary exploded!
- Oh no!
- So sad.
- Hercules is sleeping.
- Oh, big news.
- Won't bother us.
- [Joel] That is a
juicy cut of beef.
So juicy and oily and good.
- [Crow] Let's see how Mr.
Rockford does without any water.
- [Tom] Can God himself
make a plot so complicated
that even he can't
comprehend it?
- [Joel] Gee Davy...
(upbeat music)
- [Crow] That's the Blue Lagoon.
- [Tom] No, no, I think
it's James A. Michener's
Adventures in Paradise.
- [Soldier] Move along,
don't be so slow!
- [Joel] Okay, now
stay with the tour,
over here is where they
filmed Hercs-a-Poppin
and Hercules 69 and
of course Grease 2.
♪ Shake shake shake ♪
♪ Shake your booty ♪
- [Crow] Come on, everybody.
- [Joel] Wonder
what they wanted?
- [Crow] Say, now
that is a micro mini.
- [Joel] Mm-hmm.
Seen my pants?
(rustling)
- [Androcles] Hey.
- [Crow] Thanks for kicking me.
- That water can't be far off.
- [Joel] Ah, it's
right behind you.
- We should leave
before the sun goes down.
- Right over there.
- [Tom] You are gonna
fry and age prematurely.
- Look yonder.
There in that direction
is the mysterious country.
If we can find it with
the aid of the gods
we can confront the
danger that's menacing us.
- What makes you so sure
the gods will help us?
- [Crow] Chew on that.
- I'll go and look
for the men now,
I can't believe that rats
gnawed those water bags.
Human rats with swords, maybe.
Certainly not the best of men
for an enterprise like this.
- [Tom] Teenagers!
- Sleep well, don't
trouble yourself,
I'll wake you just
before we go aboard.
- Go ahead, honey.
- Yeah.
- [Tom] Hercules, sleeping
all the time, buffalo shots,
I don't need this.
Perseus, now there's
a man I could,
(muttering)
tosses Hercules.
- [Crow] A planet where
apes evolved from man?
(ominous music)
- [Joel] Man Dance '92.
- Help!
- It's clop clop for men.
A round table when?
- [Crow] Come on, everybody,
we're beatin' up on stinky!
(vocalizing)
- [Joel] Hey, do you guys
remember why we're doing this?
- [Tom] No, I'm in the film
and I don't even
know what's going on.
- [Crow] Well let's
get out of here
or our careers are done for!
- They're on the shore
but you stay below.
- [Hylas] Just let
me see the sky.
- You think doing
that's all just--
- [Crow] I have my
rights, I have my rights,
it was baby Callahan!
(crying)
- [Hylas] No, no, I'm coming up.
- Wait, the soldiers
are coming back!
- [Joel] Oh, I didn't
need those fingers anyway!
(yelling)
(doors whooshing)
- Joel, do you think
there's such a thing
as good-natured brawling?
- Oh, I never really
thought about it,
sometimes when you see--
(yelling)
Oh, why you dirty...
- I would not do
that if I were you!
(yelling)
- That's it, out you pixies go
to the door, out the window!
- Oh yeah, well I'm gonna mop
the barroom floor with you!
(yelling)
- What in tarnation?
(growling)
- Huh?
(yelling)
(groaning)
He's cracking up, Frank,
we've finally done it!
- Ew.
(chuckling)
- Oh that was fun.
Now what was your
question again?
I'm kidding, of course.
Yes there is such a thing
as good-natured brawling.
- [All] We'll be right back.
- I want Joe Frazier,
I want Joe Frazier.
(upbeat music)
(chuckling)
- Oh, that's fun.
- It makes you feel good.
- [Crow] I'm sorry.
Hey, it's a
personal-pan Hercules.
- [Tom] Herc on a
raft, wreck 'em.
- Hercules!
♪ Little Audrey's day ♪
What?
I'm trying to get a
little shut eye here.
- Hercules!
- I'm the Herc.
- [Tom] Oh, Vic Damone.
- Hercules!
(yelling)
- [Crow] Oh.
- [Hercules] Oh omnipotent Zeus.
- [Tom] Hi, Zeus is
not in right now,
but if you'd like to
leave a message...
- Hear my plea.
- [Crow] Not guilty
by reason of insanity.
- If Androcles is still alive.
♪ In the year 3535 ♪
- Grant me that we
might meet again.
- [Tom] You think we
could pan with him here?
- Oh Zeus, my father.
- [Crow] I'm not your real
father, it was Poseidon.
(coughing)
- [Joel] Herc, don't swim until
an hour after you've slept.
- [Crow] Even in the water
Murray's wigs don't come off.
- [Joel] Oh, I recognize
that, that's from Star Trek.
- [Crow] Oh yeah.
- [Joel] He's landed on
the Captain Crunch Island.
- [Tom] Rock Candy baby.
This isn't gonna be so bad.
(chuckling)
- [Crow] Say, are
you a captive woman?
- Kill me.
- With kindness.
- Kill me, I beg you.
- Do not fear, I
will not harm you.
- Please put an end
to this torment.
Kill me.
- I love you like a rock.
- What god persecutes you?
- Go away, stranger, go away.
- Who has imprisoned you?
- He was a man like you
but he can be everything,
a great serpent, water,
a terrible tempest.
- All men are alike.
- The air that you breathe,
the earth you walk
upon, go away.
No one knows in what
form he will next appear.
- Who is the monster
who threatens you?
- Proteus.
- Protein?
He's pure protein?
- Watch out!
- Is that him?
- Save yourself!
It's him, it's Proteus!
- Behind the old man?
- Go away.
- Leon Russell?
- I don't want
intruders on my island.
- [Crow] But sir, if
you'd just consider
these magazine subscriptions.
- Or you'll be
dead by nightfall.
(ominous music)
(thunder booming)
- Oh no!
- Ah!
- [Tom] Oh, they're
on the Far Side.
- [Crow] They got a dog.
- [Joel] Watch out
for the backdraft
'cause it isn't that good.
(yelling)
- [Crow] Now Herc's doing his
Nastassja Kinski impression.
Snakes away.
- [Joel] Sit Booboo, sit, stay.
(roaring)
- Kitty.
- Suddenly it's an MGM film.
(roaring)
- [Crow] What'd you
have to hit me for?
- [Tom] Hey, it's
Lion Buscaglia.
(laughing)
- Hey.
- [Tom] Give me a hug.
- Basic Instinct.
- I'll say.
- Hey!
(laughing)
- Whoa!
(gobbling)
It's the turkey
from Room Service!
- [Crow] Now he's Tippi Hendren.
- [Joel] Watch out for the
string, Herc, it'll cut ya!
(gobbling)
- [Crow] Hah, I'm back!
I'll be your tour
guide through Hell!
(chattering)
- [Joel] Dino.
Steam dragon,
steamin' mad at Herc.
(chuckling)
- [Crow] Daryl Dragon.
- [Joel] I love it when men
and lizards fight over me.
- [Tom] Herc's gonna get warts.
(chuckling)
Young and beautiful, some
day your looks will be gone.
(chuckling)
It's Gordon Gecko.
- [Crow] I'm not slimy,
take it back, take it back!
- [Joel] Oh, he's a karma
chameleon, they come and go.
- They come and go.
- Mm-hmm.
- [Tom] Look, I'm just
not a touchy person.
(groaning)
- [Crow] Note to
myself, next time,
turn into something
without a horn.
- [Tom] Ooh, you are
one spooky lizard.
- [Joel] Oh, he's gonna need
some Neosporin, definitely.
Ugh.
- [Crow] I'm sorry I did
that, that's so disgusting.
- [Joel] Hmm.
- Say.
- Well now you're free.
Oops.
- [Tom] Hello?
I guess you can get
blood from a stone, huh?
- [Crow] Boy, the graffiti's
gettin' bad around here.
- [Joel] Mm-hmm.
- [Tom] U2, live at Red Rocks.
- I'm saved.
- Yes, Proteus is dead.
That is his blood.
This rocky cliff, the whole
island is Proteus himself.
- [Joel] Wow, he's big!
- He nourished himself
on the blood of you
and other victims,
but now it's all over.
- You think so?
It was my people who
left me as a sacrifice
to prevent him from
destroying them.
- [Tom] Oh, nice.
- When you killed him you went
against the will of the gods.
- [Tom] It was cool!
- Without the help of the gods
I would never have succeeded
in slaying that monster.
- Buy me a drink?
- And the gods
will help us again.
- [Joel] Like this
beautiful breeze they sent.
(ethereal music)
♪ The Simpsons ♪
(vocalizing)
- There's my country, Atlantis!
- [Joel] Atlantis?
Oh, that's where the
Superstation comes from.
- [Tom] Conveniently
located too.
Looks like a race of polyps.
(groaning)
- [Crow] Well, I'm glad
they hired sim security.
- [Tom] Hey.
(vocalizing)
- [Crow] It's like everyone's
lost their contacts.
(chuckling)
They're looking for them.
(vocalizing)
- [Joel] Wait for
me, wait for me!
I know I have one credit left
but I'm missing my graduation!
- Today is dedicated to Uranus.
- Well thank you, I'm flat--
- The queen is in the temple
for the sacred ceremony.
- [Joel] Can I keep my thong on?
- [Tom] Geez, for me
I better beat cheeks.
- [Crow] Everyone get down
and praise Hercules' anus!
- [Joel] That's not
what they meant.
- Well that's what she said.
- I know, but...
- [Tom] Hey, Jim
Henson's Gandhi Babies.
- No, no, my only son, no!
They can't take my son from me!
- I hate hecklers.
- No, no, no!
- [Tom] Conform,
come on, conform.
- And those children
are dedicated to Uranus.
They're going to the
Mountain of the Dead.
- [Crow] Wow, that's
cool, is that a Six Flags'
Mountain of the Dead?
(triumphant music)
- [Tom] Ladies and
gentlemen, please welcome
the King family.
(applauding)
(vocalizing)
- [Crow] Look at
that guy up there.
(groaning)
Hey, could somebody
help me with this thing?
- [Joel] Excellent
copper buffalo shot.
- [Tom] Hey look, they
worship the cuckoo
for Cocoa Puffs guy.
(ominous music)
- [Joel] You kids take those
horses outside right now!
- [Crow] All right, fill
'em up and give me a lube
and a wash and wash
the inside too.
♪ Here comes the king, here
comes the big number one ♪
(vocalizing)
- Antinea.
- Hi, I'm a new character.
- Forgive me if I
interrupt the ceremony,
but the mists that protect
our island have vanished
as if by magic.
- Say, who's the new girl?
- I saw it from the mountain.
It's now my fear that Atlantis
can be seen by mortal eyes.
- Uranus has abandoned us!
- Speak for yourself!
- That explains his anger.
Listen to the thunder over
on the great mountain!
We must sacrifice to Proteus.
- Wait!
Proteus does not need
human victims any longer.
- You dare interfere,
who are you?
- Hercules of Thebes!
- My card!
- My father, the omnipotent
Zeus, has guided me here
to your land!
(suspenseful music)
- [Tom] Hey, you guys are
supposed to be nice to me,
today is dedicated to my--
- We know.
(groaning)
- [Crow] Gymkata!
- Let him alone.
No mortal has ever
dared set foot
on the sacred island
of Atlantis before.
- [Joel] Well, she's got
a point, guys, let's blow.
- What are you doing here?
- Selling band candy.
- What foolhardy reason
has led you to defy
the ire of our god?
- I do not believe in evil gods,
such gods I have
been taught to hate.
I forbid gods which
demand human sacrifices--
- Cool painting.
- And slake their thirst
with human blood, for this
reason I have slain Proteus
and saved the life of a maiden--
- Joanne Woodward.
- Who was sacrificed
to his monstrous fury.
- You lie!
- [Crow] Oh!
- [Tom] Maybe I
do, maybe I don't
all I know is I'm
outta here, bye.
- [Joel] Kristy McNichol?
(gasping)
- Wow.
- I'm here, mother.
(upbeat music)
- There was no need to sacrifice
the daughter of a queen.
(gentle instrumental music)
You are the daughter of Antinea.
You are my daughter.
If you had to die--
- I wouldn't mind.
- It was for a far more noble
and fatal reason than that.
- [Tom] 'Tis a far, far better
thing than I have ever done.
- What reason?
- Your destiny is
bound to mine, Ismene.
Just as mine is
bound to my kingdom.
- [Joel] And my kingdom
is bound to Fred's kingdom
and Fred's kingdom is
bound to Murray's kingdom.
- Have the same meaning for me,
unfortunately
nothing has changed.
On the day that a
daughter of mine
shall survive me, it is
written in the sacred books
Atlantis shall be destroyed.
- Mother, then I...
- You must die.
- [Crow] Boy, she's
really strict.
- No, I don't want to die.
- I want to live!
I want to live and laugh and
love at life and and live!
(crying)
- [Joel] You stop or I'll give
you something to cry about.
(crying)
- Take her away.
- [Tom] And if you
don't die willingly,
I'm going to ground
you, young lady.
- I really admire what
you did back there,
just wanted to say
that, not because,
there's gonna be three
extra people for dinner,
should I, oh never mind,
I'll come back later.
We're outta here, let's go.
(suspenseful music)
(vocalizing)
- John?
- Marsha
- John!
- Marsha!
- Oh John!
- John, John, John!
- Marsha, Marsha, Marsha!
- [Tom] John, Marsha.
(distorted warbling)
- [Joel] Oh, he bumped into
the invisible synthesizer.
- [Tom] Ooh!
- [Crow] Ah, you
wouldn't understand.
- Androcles, wait!
Androcles, why didn't you--
- Oh, hay fever huh?
(whistling)
- [Joel] Gosh, I'm sorry,
I thought you were
someone I used to date.
(mysterious music)
- No, it's not possible.
- What is not possible?
- [Crow] Going faster
than the speed of light?
- That man.
I saw myself it was Androcles.
- Androcles?
I don't understand.
(scoffing)
- Androcles, A N D R--
- I don't understand myself.
I'm sure I saw my
friend Androcles.
And yet...
- I don't doubt your words.
- Just your intelligence.
- I suppose you think
I've lost my mind?
Even I now seem only
to have dreamed it all.
- [Crow] A planet where
apes evolved from--
- Quite normal, often the
desire to see a loved one
creates the illusion
of seeing visions.
- Thank you Dr Joyce Brothers.
- Yes, perhaps you're right.
- Besides, you are weary
from your long journey,
seeing nothing but death
and hardship along the way.
You might relax and
put your mind at peace
with more pleasant things.
- [Joel] Why does
she always have
a Catholic processional
behind her?
- [Tom] Don't know.
♪ Standing on a beach
with a gun in my hand ♪
- [Crow] Wake up,
Linda Hunt is here!
- Hylas, wake up, there
are horsemen coming!
- Would you leave me in peace?
I've been waiting for this
for days, now I wanna sleep.
- [Tom] Christopher Walken.
- Get up, they're coming closer!
One of the men is carrying
a girl with him, it looks
like she's a prisoner.
- A girl?
- [Crow] A girl, I'm
a Grimwald warrior!
- [Joel] How's my 'do?
- [Crow] It'll do.
- [Tom] I tell ya, this
would really be exciting
if I knew what was going on.
Smoke bomb.
(suspenseful music)
- [Joel] Oh look, somebody
threw a cherry bomb
over there.
- Oh, cool.
- [Tom] Right in the toilet.
- Put her down and
tie her to that stake.
- [Crow] I'm tired of
steak too, I want chicken!
Oh.
- [Tom] Sir, did you get
your validation sticker?
- Why wait 'til sunset,
let's kill her now.
- And beat the rush.
- That's orders of Antinea.
(suspenseful music)
When it's time, we'll
throw her from the cliffs
to the rocks below.
Don't you look at me like that.
We're merely
obeying your mother.
- [Crow] I was only
following orders,
I love my adopted country!
- What are you doing?
- I'm saving that girl,
do you want to see 'em kill her?
- No, but I don't wanna save
her by getting killed myself.
- I have my rights, I have my
rights, his name was Callahan!
- [Joel] Pizza pizza.
(groaning)
(suspenseful music)
I've got a headache
this big and it's oof.
- [Crow] Head Injury
Playhouse says,
"Don't let this happen to you."
- [Tom] He's dead, Jim.
(suspenseful music)
Hey.
♪ They smile in your face ♪
♪ All the time they want
to take your place ♪
♪ Backstabbers ♪
(yelling)
- [Tom] Exit, stage left,
Heavens to Murgatroyd.
(suspenseful music)
- [Crow] I see
London, I see France.
- [Tom] Lot more than that.
♪ Everybody must get stoned ♪
- [Tom] Tonight's episode,
Jack and Jill when up the hill
to fetch a pail of murder.
(suspenseful music)
- Are there any others?
- No, I speared the last one.
- [Crow] I have my
rights, I have my rights!
- [Joel] That's good.
- [Crow] Ooh, dibs, I call dibs!
- [Tom] It takes me longer
'cause my legs are shorter.
- We're here to protect you.
- Courage!
- It's no use, it's no use.
- Why say that?
- [Crow] I can't make a decent
cup of coffee.
- Where can I go?
No matter where, it's my
destiny that I die now.
- Don't be foolish,
who'd wanna kill you?
What kind of people live here?
- Unfriendly and
somewhat nervous.
- Fly for your lives at
once, they'll kill you too.
They've possibly already
killed the great Hercules.
- Hercules, is he far away?
- Do you know him?
- Know him?
He was in my physics class!
- Don't worry now.
If he's here we're all safe.
- I'm a little drummer boy.
Oh wow.
- Fondue?
- [Tom] Ladies and gentlemen,
we are proud to introduce
the June Taylor Dancers.
(vocalizing)
- [Crow] Hah, they're dancing
to Uncle Meat by Frank Zappa.
- [Tom] Sounds like Dog Breath,
in the Year of the Plague.
♪ Primer me carucha, Chevy '39 ♪
- [Joel] Oh, Richard Pryor.
They die for their art.
- We in Greece--
- D Y E.
- Are interested in
the graces in art,
those magical apparitions.
- [Tom] Please sir,
keep the table talk
to a minimum.
- What you witness
is not magic, but nature itself.
Here in Atlantis we
try to subjugate nature
to our own scope.
- I am satisfied
with nature as it is,
savage and gentle
at the same time.
- Like me.
- Cruel and yet generous.
- Perhaps that is
because your strength
and your courage make
it possible for you
not to be afraid of the
mysteries of the universe.
- Why, do you fear them?
- I asked you first.
- Perhaps.
(laughing)
- It's Topol.
- The smoker's tooth polish?
- [Joel] No, the
hard-to-work-with actor.
- [Crow] Oh.
- [Joel] Dreezle,
drazzle, drazzle, drome,
time for this one to come home.
(mysterious music)
This is wild, I swear.
- Why are you so
anxious to leave?
- [Joel] Well some
of us have to work.
- Have you enjoyed my company?
- I must find Androcles,
I shall have no peace
until I discover what
has happened to him.
- Perhaps your friend is dead?
Perhaps his body lies at
the bottom of the sea?
- Maybe.
- Thanks, that's very, hey...
- But at least for now
it is not possible.
- What a pity.
- In the city.
- [Crow] Let's split.
- Tomorrow I shall place
at your disposal a ship
so that you may
continue your search.
There is only one
thing that I ask,
you must promise me
that you will return.
(upbeat music)
- Hit me.
- All right, one,
and you sir are on
Arts and Literature.
Okay, Tom.
- Okay.
- In Shakespeare's
Merchant of Venice, Tom,
what was the name of the
title character, Tom?
- The Beatles?
- No, I'll give you a
hint, it's not Shylock,
he was the Merchant
of Venice, anything?
- I'm afraid I'm gonna have
to stick with The Beatles.
- You still don't
get it, do you?
- Hey studs.
- Hi.
- Hey, check this out, I've
found a listing for Hercules
in The History of the
Gods, isn't that cool?
- Yeah, neat, Lucille Ball?
- Well then perhaps I'm
the only one interested
in the fact that Hercules--
- Peter Falk?
- Was also known Heracles,
Hercules the Great,
Hercules the Hero, Son
of Zeus and Alcmene
and he was driven
into insanity by Hera
who later restored his sanity.
- That's really neat,
Crow, Jimmy Hoffa?
- Nope.
- D'oh!
- Well then perhaps you
Philistines will be interested
to know that
Hercules, quote, was,
"Scrawny and
underdeveloped as a child,
"he became interested
in body building
"only after an unknown
but shameful incident
"in the boys' locker
room in at age 15."
- It doesn't say that,
let me see that book.
- Ah, tut tut, you're
not interested.
- Come on, Joel, let
him read a little more.
- It goes on to say,
"Hercules was not known for
"his intellect, in fact he was
dumber than a box of sticks.
"It has been said that Hercules
"couldn't outwit a staple gun.
"In fact, both hands
and a flashlight
"were not enough for
Hercules to find his--"
- He's making this up!
Come on, it doesn't say that.
- It does too, dickweed!
- Oh!
- Come on Tom, let him finish.
Go ahead, Crow.
- Thanks.
Here, I'll skip down to the
stuff about his son, Hiness.
Here it is.
- Hiness?
- "Hiness never lived up to
"the impossible standards set
by his steroid-popping father.
"Unable to fulfill the
role of a demi-god,
"Hiness drifted aimlessly
and eventually fell in
"with an experimental
Minneapolis theater group
"called The Orange Hyena.
"Their nude production
of Blithe Spirit set in a
"Texas prison was seen by four
people in its two-week run."
- Joel, he's making all this up.
- Come on, Crow, is
this stuff for real?
- Yeah, it says here,
"After flunking out
"of locksmith school, Hiness
drifted for four years,
"stopping at his
father's home only twice
"and then just long
enough to eat a sandwich
"over the kitchen sink
with his girlfriend Tamara,
"an exotic dancer.
"Every so often Hercules
would see his son's
"yellow '72 Charger
in the driveway
"and would know that Hiness
was home to ask for money.
"On one occasion
Hercules sat him down
"to talk over a 12 pack
of Mickey's big mouths.
"Before long it disintegrated
from bitter accusations--"
- Okay, Crow, I
think that is enough.
You know, folks,
history really is fun,
especially when you
make it up yourself.
(alarm blaring)
- Oh, we've got movies on!
- Don't you want to hear
about the intervention?
(doors whooshing)
- Put that book away.
- It's good stuff though.
- Here, drink this wine.
- [Joel] Oh, don't do it, Herc.
The same old same old.
- [Tom] No, don't,
you'll be killed
or rendered unconscious.
- Oh boy, come back.
- Oh, too late.
- Will he ever learn?
- He didn't swallow.
- Hmm?
- [Tom] You're right,
he didn't swallow.
- I hope that tomorrow
you will have decided
to remain here for
as long as you wish,
even for the rest of your life.
(mumbling)
- [Joel] Oh, we'll be leaving
now, come on, Gretchen.
- Is it working yet?
- No, nothing.
- [Tom] Do you
feel any different?
Just wondering, just kind of...
Wanna lay down, okay good.
- [Crow] I'm so sleepy I
could sleep for a week.
- [Tom] Heh, looks like bongos.
Oh, it all looks so
good, where do I start?
Oh yes.
(mysterious music)
- [Joel] Hey, hey man, wake up.
Herc.
- Hey man.
- [Joel] You know,
after my senior year
my tolerance level
was just like so high
it didn't matter any more.
(groaning)
- [Crow] Spit take.
(thudding)
- [Joel] I'll get it later, oh.
- Bronson Pinchot?
- Bronze silver?
- [Joel] Lee Greenwood?
- Only two men managed
to overcome 10 of you?
- Antinea, send me
back with new men.
I assure you this time they
won't get away, I beg you.
I swear it, such a thing
won't happen again.
- Yes, you're right.
It won't happen again.
- [Tom] 'Cause you're fired.
- Not the commode!
- Oh, no!
- [Joel] Oh I knew it,
death by chocolate.
- Oh don't kill me!
- Don't make me take a bath!
- [Crow] Let me watch
Creature Feature, c'mon Mom!
- [Joel] You can't do that,
I've got tubes in my ears,
you're gonna get
in trouble so bad!
(yelling)
- [Crow] Ooh, it's gonna
kill him but it'll do wonders
for his arthritis.
(bubbling)
- Is it too late
to request a last meal?
- [Crow] Another Jenny
Craig success story.
- But Antinea, I've
had to imprison--
- [Joel] Yes, I mind
very much if you smoke.
- He could easily be dangerous.
- Dangerous for who?
- Why do they worship
the Banana Splits?
- Dangerous for Atlantis.
- I am the Queen of
Atlantis, it is I
who decides about
life and death.
- Who died and made you God?
- Open it!
- [Joel] In retrospect, it
was a dumb place to hide.
(mysterious music)
- Poor Androcles, too
fragile for the weight
he had to support.
Now somebody else
will sit on the throne
that was destined for him.
- And it ain't gonna be me.
- Hercules.
- Ew.
- Gee.
- [Tom] What, what, you
comin' on to me or what?
- Take him to the
valley and let him die
like the rest of the weaklings.
♪ Everything is
beautiful at the valley ♪
- And then go find me
Ismene and kill her.
Kill her!
(ominous music)
- [Joel] Blocked, cocked
and ready to rock.
- [Tom] Hey, can I get
some service in here?
- [Crow] Seen it!
- [Joel] Oh man,
this is his only bit.
(groaning)
- [Tom] You know, some of
these are just for me, folks.
- [Crow] Why does he even
bother to bend 'em back?
(groaning)
- He's a showoff.
- [Tom] That used to be easy
for me, I'm gettin' up there,
full-grown son, little
gray around the temples.
- [Joel] Alfred
Hitchcock presents.
(yelling)
- Better get back in there,
I picked the wrong window.
- [Joel] James
Brolin in The Car.
- [Tom] Jeez, will you
look at that idiot Hercules
up on the ledge, would
you stop and help him?
- [Crow] Nah, he'll
just kill himself.
- [Tom] That's all right.
Taxi, taxi!
- One, two, three, pinned!
- Snicker snag on him.
- Yeah!
(groaning)
- [Joel] Oh yeah, the horse,
I got a little tied
up with the guy.
- [Crow] That was good, Herc,
I was with you all the time.
Careful, white white white
is the color of our carpets.
(suspenseful music)
- He couldn't have escaped
through the window,
the bars are intact!
- Where is he?
He can't have disappeared.
Find him if you value your life!
- [Tom] I don't really
value my life, so...
- [Joel] Guys, it's
the Wonder Bread chart,
check it out, see?
- [Crow] Oh this is so
nice, just you, me and him.
- [Tom] Okay, things
get rough we eat
the little guy, agreed?
- Agreed.
- The soldiers!
- Run for your life!
- [Joel] This is
not a drill, people!
♪ That's the night the
lights went out in Georgia ♪
(suspenseful music)
- [Tom] Go back for a time.
- [Crow] Special
delivery, Mr. Rogers.
- [Joel] Hey, I used
to lift with that guy.
♪ Hello, hello, hello, hello ♪
- They've got Androcles,
let's go after them.
- You're mad, they'll kill you!
- [Crow] Champagne for
breakfast, you're mad!
- Let's see where
they put him, come on.
- Here come some more!
- They've got s'mores!
- [Timoteo] Scatter,
scatter, scatter!
- [Tom] Geez, we're not gonna
get anything done today.
- Did you hurt yourself?
- No.
- [Timoteo] It's Hercules!
- [Crow] Hurry, Diana!
- [Tom] Hercules, I hope
he doesn't fall asleep
at the wheel there.
- Wait, Hercules, wait!
- [Crow] Ah great, the next
Hercules doesn't come 'til 9:47.
(suspenseful music)
- Sergeant!
- Yes, sir?
- Halt!
- You bringing us
another customer?
- It's James Mason.
- Yes, there he is.
Take him down and
lower him into the pit.
- And feed all the rest of
them while you're there.
- [Tom] Might as well kill
two birds with one stone,
you know what I mean?
- [Joel] Visit scenic Lake Herc.
- Ride the Herc.
- Ride the dogs.
(adventurous music)
- [Tom] Huh, fella could get
to like a place like this.
- [Joel] You know, it's really
amazing there aren't any
tourists here,
think I'll go nude.
- [Tom] Um...
- [Crow] I think the camera
man's falling asleep.
You know, it's
possible that this is
the stupidest part of this film.
- [Tom] Huh.
Looks like even Hercules
is bored by this.
- [Crow] Pizza pizza.
- [Joel] You see
guys, in the old days
they didn't even take the
cheese out of the goat
before they served it, see?
(vomiting)
- [Tom] Number 11, your
order's up, number 11.
- [Crow] Hey, the
dead goat's here!
(cheering)
- [Tom] That looks like
a Roadrunner cartoon.
- [Crow] Meep meep, meep meep.
- [Tom] From that perspective
and the way that it comes.
Is that, ah, don't do that!
- [Joel] Kids come a-running
for the good taste of raw goat.
- Mmm.
- Oh, it's head soup.
♪ Ooh, it's rainin'
goat, hallelujah ♪
(chuckling)
- Who wants white meat?
- Who wants gray meat?
(vomiting)
(chuckling)
- [Tom] Ah, here comes dessert.
- Ah.
- There's always room.
- [Joel] Wait a minute.
- [Crow] Aw look, you can
see the string he's hanging,
how, fake!
- Oh brother.
- Fake!
- Oh jeez.
Jockey for slaves.
- Boy, I see London.
(chuckling)
- What are you going to do?
- [Joel] Owie.
Owie!
- Hercules, they're too
many, if we were helped by
the men of the valley we'd be
able to finish 'em off easier.
- Can we set them free?
- Down there, there's
a barricade, we
gotta break it down.
- [Crow] I wanna take
a picture, step back.
- [Joel] Ooh!
(yelling)
Forget it, I'll do it.
- [Ismene] Even if you
should break through,
the guards would hear, it's
better to run, hide ourselves.
- If my father finds
me here with a girl--
- [Crow] He'd be surprised.
- He'll never let
me out of the house,
I'd better do something useful
before he gets hold of me.
- [Joel] I'll mow the lawn.
(screaming)
- It's the tin man brigade.
- [Joel] Sorry, I'm a coward!
- [Tom] Ooh.
- [Crow] Number 2,000
pencil works every time!
- [Tom] Thanks for
all the help, Sherry.
- [Crow] Hmm?
- [Ismene] You get off him!
- [Tom] Huh?
Now the original Broadway
cast of Godspell.
They're mad.
- [Joel] Hey, just let
me unlock it, all right?
- [Tom] Wait, wait, wait, wait!
- [Crow] It opens the other way.
- Hercules, look there,
the soldiers are coming!
- [Tom] Aw criminy, I don't
even have the table set.
- [Joel] He's got no
new material, does he?
- [Crow] He's passing a stone!
(laughing)
- Oh, right in the head!
- [Tom] Ow.
School's out, man, woo!
- [Hylas] It's Androcles!
- [Crow] Hey, David
Brenner's in there.
Androcles is down and
Hercules acts quickly
on Emergency 911, Spock.
- [Joel] 'Scuse me,
I'm a slave escaping
and I really gotta...
- [Tom] Ooh, just
set that anywhere.
- All right, clamp.
- Clamp.
- Sponge.
- Needle.
- Suture, needle.
- Sponge, clamp.
- Suture.
- May Zeus be praised.
- [Crow] Oh, thank you
so bloody much, Zeus!
- To the barricade,
prisoners are escaping!
Kill every one of them!
- [Joel] Except for
Chopper, he's the funny one!
(laughing)
(vocalizing)
(murmuring)
- The soldiers!
- [Joel] Soldiers crystals!
(yelling)
- [Tom] Your sticks and
stones may break our bones
but ow, ooh, ow!
(yelling)
- Alter mount!
- That's why the
stones are there.
(laughing)
Bad one, ouch.
- Sad, really.
- Hey!
See these wounds, these open
sores that cover our bodies?
- They make me happy!
- Antinea who's done this,
treating us like animals!
And every day we curse the
fates who keep us alive
and that monstrous queen
who put us here to starve!
- But why?
- [Crow] Because she didn't
feed us and we've got
these sores and geez,
I covered that already.
- There in the Mountain of
the Dead is a miraculous rock
which has the power
to change all men.
- Change men, what do you mean?
- I don't know!
I only know that we are doomed.
Every year the guards of
Antinea choose the children
destined to be changed by
the rock and its powers.
- [Tom] Murray, the
sensitive leper.
(sniffing)
- You smell great, Carl.
- Those boys that I saw?
- Yes, we were like them
before we were taken to the
mountain, many years ago.
Look at us now, we are the
few who resisted the rock
and its influence.
Those who succumbed have
never been seen since.
- 'Cause maybe they're dead?
- Many say they now live
in the world of
the supernatural,
creatures of evil, invincible.
- [Tom] Hmm, they
up there somewhere?
- Say that again.
- I'll go to the mountain.
- Better to attack Atlantis!
- No, Hercules is right!
- Ah, leper model.
- We will never be really free
until we destroy the power
of that rock forever!
I will go with you.
- [Joel] I don't like you.
- Wait for me here and
take care of Androcles.
When I return we shall
decide what to do.
- Yes, Father.
- Come along.
♪ And hear Alexander's
Ragtime Band ♪
(murmuring)
- [Tom] Gee, Herc, help
yourself to my horse, I guess.
- Goodbye, goodbye!
- Goodbye!
- [Joel] So, did you
hear, my dad's outta town.
- Don't be sad.
- Why?
- Just wait.
- [Tom] 'Cause I'm
the only woman here.
- We'll go to Greece together.
Life is different there and
in Spring it's unbelievable.
- [Joel] But I gotta go back
to school next semester.
- We'll just think about all
our today's and our tomorrows.
- [Joel] Could you run that by
me again, how many tomorrows?
- Stranger, come!
- Keep your eyes peeled!
Ooh, sorry, sorry.
(groaning)
- Stop, you're all mad!
- [Tom] Yeah we're
mad, can you blame us?
Look at us.
- The lepers are revolting!
- I'll say!
(chuckling)
- If you're afraid, stay
here with your father
but we want our revenge!
- [Joel] Well, I
really did a good job
cooling them off, I guess.
- Revenge rhubarb!
- Well how'd it go
and what did they say?
- Look after
Androcles and Ismene.
- I'll guard 'em with my life.
- Hylas!
(ethereal music)
- [Crow] I hope that's pudding.
(crying)
- [Tom] Anyone who says
winning isn't everything
has never won
anything, just do it.
(mysterious music)
(hissing)
- [Joel] Wow, really cool fort.
- Now, let's see, didn't
we park on level four?
- [Joel] You know,
Hercules, this would make
an excellent
conceptual nightclub.
- [Tom] You know, it could be
kind of a workout nightclub.
- Yeah!
- It's got chiseled granite,
some steel, glass.
- We'll have concepts all over
with video monitors and such.
- [Tom] Lifecycles and
cocktail Lifecycles, oh boy.
Hmm.
- [Crow] Suddenly I'm huge.
- There, there.
- Bad dog, bad dog!
- An evil for all men.
- But somebody wrecked it.
- Down there is the Fari Rock
which holds the secret
of life or death.
- [Joel] Look,
Chet, I think you're
reading too much into this.
- You think I'm mad?
- [Tom] Well, I believe you
believe what you're saying.
- Is that it?
- No I don't think you're mad.
Cuckoo!
- You can't believe
that a piece of rock can
destroy a man as we know him.
You can't believe
that a piece of rock
can change bodies
as well as minds.
- [Tom] Well, I believe
that for every drop of rain
that falls a flower grows.
- But it also brings death!
With dead men who
walk, Hercules!
Unbelievable horrors!
- [Crow] You fruitcake.
(ominous music)
He's a disco inferno!
- [Tom] Burn the mother down.
(upbeat music)
- Now, after much searching,
Antinea's found the mystic
secrets of Uranus and will
use them to make herself
omnipotent, destroying
all mankind and the gods.
- You are a priest, Zayned,
how can you speak so
of death and destruction?
- I was the last high priest
dedicated to Uranus.
(groaning)
- [Tom] Gonna wear longer
skirts from now on.
- Sacred shrine while
serving forever.
- Uranus was a just god.
- Uranus was a good cop!
- If what you say
is true, Zayned,
this stone must be destroyed,
it has already
caused too much evil.
- The blood of
Uranus can never be--
(groaning)
- Oh, why?
- The rock of the gods
will only lose its power
when touched by a force
above and beyond this Earth
on which we live.
- You know the secret of
this force, Zayned, tell me.
- [Crow] It's pudding,
I don't know why.
- I can reveal to only one
man the secret mysteries
of the gods but he must show me
that he is stronger
than the rock itself.
Take this bar, Hercules.
- [Tom] Keep it as
my free gift to you.
- [Crow] That's it,
that's all he has to do?
- [Joel] Mm-hmm.
This Hercules is
dumber than I remember.
(intense music)
- [Crow] So you took
shop class, big deal.
- [Tom] He's dreamy.
- Zeus, Father, help me.
- [Crow] Help me, Zeus.
- I do not do this out of pride.
This you know.
It is only to cause
their hearts of stone
to swell up with pity.
To let their eyes
fill with tears,
the tears of common humanity.
Do not abandon me in this trial.
- [Tom] Oh nice, you
know, this would make
another good monologue for
young American actors on the go.
(mysterious music)
- [Joel] Hercules is
seeking the perfect tan.
- Edna too.
- You've won,
Hercules of Thebes.
Only the rays of the sun can
destroy the rock of Uranus.
- You need more fiber.
- When a man can remove
that stone and a ray of
sunlight shines upon the rock,
then we will see the reign
of Antinea of Atlantis.
(gasping)
And of all its inhabitants.
- Thank you, Zayned,
and have no fear.
I shall succeed in
defeating Antinea,
without destroying Atlantis
or her inhabitants.
- [Tom] Okay.
- With the help
of my companions,
I shall put an end to her reign.
(yelling)
- [Crow] That's us,
we're his companions!
- [Tom] Companions
of Hercules, woo!
- [Joel] Huh?
A funny thing happened
on the way to the forum.
- [Tom] They made
a Hercules movie!
(vocalizing)
- Remember the Alamo!
- Storm the Bastille!
- Give us Barabbas!
- Hell no, we won't go!
- Attica, Attica!
- [Crow] Oh.
- [Tom] Atticus, so you
want a revolution huh?
- [Joel] That's what it's
like tryin' to get into
Let's Make a Deal.
- Ooh.
Well I see our neighbors
are at it again.
- [Joel] Mm-hmm.
Should I call the cops?
I'll call the cops.
(suspenseful music)
- [Tom] Looks like a job for
the Arthur Rank Organisation.
- [Crow] No more
than three items
in the fitting rooms, please.
- [Tom] Is that our cue?
That's our cue, come on
boys, that's our cue.
- [Joel] Okay, everybody,
let's have fun this time.
Come on!
♪ One singular sensation,
every little one ♪
- [Crow] Had this been an
actual emergency, you would...
♪ We love you Conrad ♪
♪ Oh yes we do ♪
- [Crow] Parthenon party!
- [Tom] I guess so.
- [Joel] Well they
stopped the revolution
to take a little nap, I see.
(snoring)
- Very good, Joel.
- Thank you.
- The money's in the...
(groaning)
- [Joel] All right then,
show of hands, who's alive?
Oh, I'm sorry.
- [Tom] I am not
cleaning this up.
- [Crow] Wow,
crowd's dead tonight,
typical Friday late show.
- Mm-hmm.
Man, this kinda took
a really dark turn.
- Where?
- Cripes, I'm in trouble,
I'm gonna get blamed for this.
Oop, pardon me, excuse me,
sorry about the head there.
Sorry, oh, pardon me.
- Oh no, those guys too.
- [Joel] Well, this
could've gone better.
(mysterious music)
- [Tom] All right, go ahead,
everything checks out.
- Antinea!
- I'm in the shower.
- [Joel] Herc is as mad as heck
and he's not gonna
take it anymore!
- [Hercules] Where's my
son, where's Androcles?
- Have no fear.
- Underdog is here!
- Your son is alive, he is safe.
- Why didn't you
have him killed?
- That was part of the deal!
- Why did you spare him?
(suspenseful music)
- Oh, hi.
- Because of you, Hercules.
Listen to me, I could
have had your son killed
and with him your friend.
I could've had you killed too.
- I just didn't feel like it.
- Perhaps I should have.
- Hindsight's 20/20 sometimes.
- For that is what
mt people advised me.
But I did not heed their advice.
- [Crow] You're on my dress.
- I wanted you to live.
I wanted you to live
because I love you.
- [Crow] Long time.
- [Joel] I'm sorry,
I wasn't listening.
- If you will join me in
the conquest of the world,
all mankind will recognize
me as their queen.
And adore you as the
one and only god.
Love me, Hercules, and together
we shall reign
over men and gods.
- [Joel] Well it sounds
good, I'm interested,
but can I sleep on it?
- [Crow] You taste
like Alan Steel.
- [Tom] You taste
like Yvonne De Carlo.
- [Joel] Wait a minute,
now you can have both.
- Hmm.
(smacking lips)
Go great together.
- And how do you expect
to conquer the world?
- [Joel] Mass mailings
and basically,
you just saturate the market.
(somber music)
(vocalizing)
♪ Swing American ♪
- [Crow] Oh, plastiface,
that is a plan, I get it.
- These are my soldiers, my men,
against which no force
in the world can combat.
Of a supreme race, born
of the blood of Uranus.
(groaning)
- You've crossed the line!
- Pick up that table, Hercules,
and hurl it away
if you're able to.
- [Joel] Heh, no problem,
do it all the time.
(grunting)
- Table for two?
(suspenseful music)
- [Tom] Sumpter will
throw the table now.
(suspenseful music)
- With this new race I
can dominate the world.
- [Joel] We'll break
tables all over the world!
- This is a mad dream, Antinea,
but I shall put an
end to the madness.
- [Joel] Uh-oh.
- [Crow] Ooh!
(vocalizing)
- [Joel] Oh, that was kinda
dumb, locking myself in,
I didn't think that
through at all.
- And he aims!
- No he doesn't.
- Oh.
- I don't think so.
(gong ringing)
- [Joel] Send in the
reinforcements, we
need reinforcements!
- [Tom] All right,
Johnson's at the plate,
he's a swift hitter, oh it's
a swing and a line drive!
- [Crow] That's it?
Oh.
- [All] Surprise!
- [Joel] Uh-oh SpaghettiOs.
- [Crow] They're all photo
negatives of Abe Lincoln.
- [Joel] Just take a
little off the sides.
- Hercules.
- [Joel] Well there's Ol Yeller.
(chuckling)
- [Crow] We've come to
your emotional rescue.
- [Joel] Hey look, behind him,
there's the Millennium Falcon.
(mysterious music)
- [Crow] It's The Police.
- [Tom] So I guess I'll just
be sending out an SOS, guys.
(laughing)
- [Crow] Wow, these guys can
stare down the best of 'em.
- [Joel] It's funny
if you think about it,
you know, queenie?
♪ We represent the
Lollipop Guild ♪
- [Tom] I'll hit you with my
giant swab, I swear I'll do it.
- [Crow] Charles Schwab?
- [Joel] What makes
those guys so scary?
- [Tom] They're super
strong, you know?
- [Crow] You've
been following this?
(doors whooshing)
- Oh hi, friends,
what you doin'?
- We made a Hercules
action figure!
- Oh wow.
- It does all kinds of
really cool stuff.
- Yeah, it can pick stuff up
over its head and throw it!
- And it does lots of
other cool stuff too.
It lies down and sleeps
for hours on end.
- Wow, it's really
neat, isn't it?
Just the way it lies there.
- Well you guys, I hate
to be critical but--
- No, no, we haven't even
told you the coolest part yet!
- It talks!
- Yeah!
- Oh, wow, really?
Well that's a Herc of a
different color isn't it?
- Yeah.
- Come on in, okay.
Let's see, why didn't you tell
me that in the first place?
I bet he says a lot
of neat action stuff.
- [Hercules] I'm so sleepy I
can barely keep my eyes open.
(laughing)
- Oh but I wanna hear
the kinda stuff he says when
he's runnin' into battle.
- [Hercules] I'm so sleepy I
can barely keep my eyes open.
- Are you sure you wanna
call this an action figure?
(sighing)
- [Hercules] I'm so sleepy I
can barely keep my eyes open.
(crying)
- I admit it, I admit it,
a Hercules action figure
is lame, really lame!
- We're failures,
total failures!
- Oh, no, come on
you guys, come on,
you put your best foot forward.
- I don't even have a foot!
- Okay, okay,
okay, that's beside
the point, okay?
You guys tried your very hardest
and you did the
very best you could
and because of that
you'll never be failures.
(sniffling)
- [Hercules] You're absolutely
right, Joel Robinson,
we'll be back after
this commercial message
from Jolly Rancher
candies, good night now.
(groaning)
(thudding)
(upbeat music)
(mysterious music)
- You okay?
- Mm-hmm.
- [Tom] Pretty funny.
- [Crow] Oh, that's no
way to treat my hinder!
- Father!
- Hylas!
- Interruptus.
- [Tom] Ooh.
- And so once again
you have disobeyed me.
- [Tom] Once again we see
there's nothing you can possess
that I cannot take away.
- Wanted to attack the city
and there wasn't any
time to stop them.
- Where are the others?
- I don't know,
Timoteo got away with
Ismene and Androcles
but when I tried to join
them I was attacked.
- [Tom] Hey, keep
it down in there!
Hey, come on, I work nights!
- And when I came to
I found myself here.
Maybe they used magic?
- It's really sturdy,
I think you should
make an offer on it.
- [Crow] Dad, come on,
you never listen to me.
I really love her and
I've still got my job
down at the garage and...
(mysterious music)
- Father, look.
- [Crow] You look, I'm bitter.
- [Joel] Hmm, forced
aromatherapy huh?
- Now I remember.
Now I know what this room is.
The mists that rose up.
- We're being Martinized.
- Androcles invoking my help.
- And all that kinda stuff
and stuff.
- This is the room where
Androcles lost his memory
and consciousness
and Antinea means
to do the same thing to us!
- Huh?
Who's Androcles and who are you?
- [Crow] It's actually
kind of soothing though.
- [Tom] Legs A,
before and after.
- [Crow] So, lunch?
- [Joel] No, this isn't
right, I haven't even
ever known the love
of a woman, Dad!
- [Tom] Glad he has
his own stud maker.
- [Crow] Hey, he
is a stud maker.
- [Joel] Oh, I hope
this doesn't mean Kiss
is gonna come in here and play.
(suspenseful music)
- [Tom] Oh great, throw salt
in our wounds why don't you?
- [Joel] Huh, that's
a real nice feature,
ceiling comes down
for easy maintenance.
(suspenseful music)
- [Tom] Um, what do you
think we should do, Dad?
Like, what do you
think, should we like
push up on it and stuff
is that gonna help?
Oh, gee, wow Dad,
you're really strong,
you've done this
kind of thing before,
should I get the flashlight,
what are you trying to do,
Dad, can I help?
- I'm gonna change
my name to Atlas.
- [Tom] Do you need any,
do you need help, Dad?
- [Joel] Yeah, grab
that crescent wrench.
- [Tom] Now which one's that,
is that the one over there?
Okay.
Can I help there?
- No, thanks Son.
Look, you know what
you can do to help?
Go set the table for
your mother, okay?
- [Tom] Okay.
- [Crow] Joseph, are you
coming to the barn raising?
- [Joel] Just set the
ceiling anywhere, Son.
- [Tom] See, that's why
these prefab dungeons
are a bad idea.
(mysterious music)
- [Joel] Yeah, thanks for
helping your old dad up, Son.
- [Tom] Sorry, Dad.
- [Crow] Big chains
for easy grip action.
(grunting)
Climbing the swag.
- [Joel] Son, don't look up
right now, for your own good.
- [Tom] You know, I really
could've helped back there, Dad.
Hey, I'm feeling kinda tingly
right now, is that wrong?
- [Joel] Oh, it'll
pass, it'll pass.
- [Tom] Okay.
Dad, what are you doing,
why are you pushing me?
(yelling)
- [Crow] When in Chicago,
see the coal mine
at the Museum of Science and
Industry on the lakefront.
- [Joel] I think I just evolved.
- [Tom] I think this
is the same ramp
where Deep Throat
met Bob Woodward.
- Who's there, halt!
- [Crow] I mean
halt, who goes there?
Shoot, I'm new, I'm new.
- [Tom] Well sorry I asked.
- [Joel] Now this
is what you do, Son,
you grab the arm and twist!
- [Tom] But I want to
be an osteopath, Dad.
Good job, Dad.
- [Joel] Geez son, this
used to be a ballpark here.
- Lead to the temple.
The other one should
lead to the sea,
go Hylas, and leave this island!
- And you, Father?
- I'll join you
as soon as I can.
- Father.
- Go, Hylas, this
time you must obey me,
it's a favor I ask.
- [Crow] I hate this part.
- Take care of your mother.
- Right.
- [Tom] Which one is she again?
- They have discovered
our escape, hurry!
- [Crow] Keep head down, keep
head down, keep head down.
(thudding)
Ooh!
- [Joel] It's beautiful.
(intense music)
- [Tom] Say.
- [Joel] Quick, 42nd
and Broadway, pronto!
- [Tom] Sir, please take
your place at the cab stand,
we've got a system...
(grunting)
- [Hercules] Hey, hey!
- [Joel] Take it out of first!
- [Crow] Ah, now
that's on purpose!
♪ Buffalo shot, won't
you come out tonight ♪
♪ Come out ♪
- [Joel] Dad would kill me if
he saw me dressed like this.
- [Crow] Whee!
(thudding)
Oh!
- [Tom] Oh look, it's
the first muscle car.
(laughing)
Lots of horses on there.
- [Joel] This looks like
a Lower Wacker Drive
chase scene, doesn't it?
- [Tom] Ah, somebody slammed
their cape in the door.
(suspenseful music)
- [Crow] I hate those
little compact car spaces.
- [Joel] You know, I was
just thinking, like wouldn't,
like one horse be a
little less cumbersome
than 40?
- Would one horse do?
(vocalizing)
Quick, all of you, hide!
(chuckling)
- Hmm.
- That's handy.
- [Joel] I'll get it,
I have to do everything
around this lousy cave!
- [Crow] Ah, the first
combustion engine.
- [Tom] Big Daddy Dunkirk
lives in the flaming
chariot from Hell!
(yelling)
- [Crow] I hope his body
grease isn't flammable.
(suspenseful music)
- [Joel] Guys, I think
Hercules exploded!
- [Tom] We've got an
overturned 10-horse chariot
on Spaghetti Junction,
you may wanna take
an alternate route this morning.
(murmuring)
(clapping)
(intense music)
- [Crow] Get off my back!
- [Joel] It's a
madhouse, a madhouse!
- Come on!
- Quit horsing around!
- [Joel] Oh look, a
dry-roasted Spartan.
- [Crow] Little fancy roll.
- [Tom] Oh my cape, it hurts,
it burns, it hurts, ow!
- [Crow] Oh, Hercules teaches
them the meaning of loss.
- [Tom] I'll say.
- [Joel] Stop, drop and roll.
- Leave the horses
and follow me!
- [Tom] I can't follow
you, I'm an inferno here!
- [Crow] Follow me if
you're flame retardant!
- [Joel] You'd think
the sprinkler system
would've kicked in by now.
- Well, ya know...
Why Hercules, I never knew.
- [Joel] Oh, watch the
wet spot, it's a doozy.
(vocalizing)
- [Crow] Oh, nevermind,
you're on your own!
- [Joel] Kansas was right,
all they are is dust
in the wind now.
(vocalizing)
(upbeat music)
(suspenseful music)
(clanging)
- [Joel] Wow, these mountains
really make you feel small.
(chuckling)
- [Tom] Hey look, wooden
ships on the water.
(screaming)
- Hylas!
(laughing)
- Hymen, put me down!
- Get you all the time!
(screaming)
- [Hylas] Where's Ismene?
- Captured, and
Androcles with her.
- [Crow] I have my
rights, I have my rights!
- I threw myself
on those soldiers.
I fought like a lion.
- And look at me,
just look at me!
(crying)
- I must've killed at least 50.
- [Tom] Here, pull my finger.
- [Hylas] Where is she?
- There, down in that ship,
she and Androcles
are to be sacrificed.
They'll set fire to
the ship and let it
drift away on the wind.
- And what about me?
Doesn't anyone think about me?
(crying)
- What did you say?
- Start yelling.
- I said...
(mumbling)
- You heard me, call for help!
- Have you lost your mind?
- I told you to call for help!
- Oh ow ow.
- [Timoteo] Help,
he's a lunatic!
Help me, please!
♪ Gonna see Miss Eliza ♪
♪ Goin' to Mississippi ♪
- [Crow] Come on, you're
carryin' that thing
like a loaf of bread.
- Louder.
- Help, I'm a sacrifice!
Help me somebody,
save me, save me!
- [Crow] Please stow
all your carry on
in the overhead compartment.
- [Hylas] I've got
another prisoner!
Raise the sail and go ashore!
- [Soldier] But we
haven't seen the signal!
- [Hylas] I carry the
queen's orders, move!
- [Joel] Say, who's
the new sacrifice?
- You're saved now.
- Hylas!
- [Hylas] Stay quiet,
stupid, and you, yell!
- [Timoteo] Help,
help, I a ruined man!
- [Crow] Meanwhile,
six weeks later.
- [Tom] Wait a minute.
(groaning)
I knew I had a 12
pack stashed in here.
(chuckling)
- [Joel] Once Herc gets
an idea, he's like a dog
with an old sock, he
just won't let go of it.
(groaning)
- [Crow] That's where
he keeps his stash
so his mom won't find it, woo!
- [Tom] Oh yeah.
- [Crow] Oh big deal!
- [Joel] Good one, Herc, you
missed it by about two feet!
- [Tom] Marion,
don't look at it!
- Slowly the sun
will move, Hercules,
and where shadow has been
bright sunlight will shine.
- [Crow] Oh great,
where were you
when I was poking
this hole in the wall?
- [Joel] Hey, let me climb
down, it's really hard to hear
from where I'm at.
Ow, stingy, the spurs
and the hurt, ouch!
- [Crow] I just wanted to
know if you wanted anything,
I'm going out.
- [Joel] I still can't hear you,
really, what?
- Leave this island!
Fates have decreed
that you shall live!
- [Tom] Oh crap, I'm
outta here, bye bye.
- [Crow] Oh, well, I
think he misunderstood,
bit slow but a good kid.
- [Joel] Oh look, he's
wearing New Balance.
(mysterious music)
(vocalizing)
- [Crow] I'm Jim
McKay and this is
Great Moments of the
Olympics, we'll be right back.
(coughing)
- [Joel] Why are they
holding rump roasts?
- [Crow] It's in
honor of your...
- Your anus.
- Oh, you.
- Take the voyage
of our warrior.
- There's the signal, I'll
set the ship on afire.
- [Tom] Oh, we're on the ship.
- [Joel] We haven't worked
out all the kinks yet.
(chuckling nervously)
- What are you doing?
- Hey!
- Who are you?
- Your worst nightmare!
♪ I'm late, I'm late for
a very important date ♪
♪ No time to say
hello, goodbye, later ♪
(intense music)
- [Joel] Whoa, I didn't think
I was gonna fit through there,
I thought I was gonna have
to grease my shoulders.
- [Tom] There he goes.
- Oh!
- That's gross.
- [Tom] Lost some
points on style, oh,
he fused his spine,
that's gonna cost him.
- [Crow] Hey, watch
the little guy, ow!
- Cut Timoteo loose.
- [Crow] Ow!
- [Joel] I'll just
set myself anywhere.
- It's Jack LaLanne!
- And his wife Elaine LaLanne.
- It's Owen Mclain.
- Look, Hercules!
- How can you tell?
- From his blowhole?
- [Tom] And he's
leaving an oil slick.
- [Joel] We're gonna get
a bigger boat, right?
- [Crow] Ooh, that's
a keeper there, eh?
Hey, get the gaff, watch
the tail, get the net.
Get the net, bring
him in, show ya.
- [Tom] And he's not wet,
ladies and gentlemen,
he's perfectly dry.
- He's a duck.
Queer old duck.
- Whoa, that thing's touchy!
- Mm-hmm,
Krakatoa used to Java.
- Pretty much.
- [Tom] Quick, get the camera.
(yelling)
- [Joel] Oh, terrific now
it's a Bell Laboratories film.
- [Crow] Women, children,
space men and sort of stylized
versions idealized
Renaissance men first!
- [Tom] Yep, see?
Good lesson here,
this is what happens
when you shake up a
can of Tahitian Treat.
- [Crow] When it's inside ya.
- [Joel] Another fourth
of July gone bad, guys.
- [Crow] Yep.
For Herc, these are
just acceptable losses.
- [Tom] Well, the Pompeii
Middle School closed.
Vesuvius Schools, Junior
and Senior closed.
- You must protect
us, mighty Uranus!
- [Joel] Bite me, I'm a statue.
- [Tom] Take a
layer of chocolate,
cover it with gooey caramel.
- That's not half bad.
- This is the closing of
Uranus Days, enjoy the finale
and be careful driving home.
- [Joel] Stop making
Uranus cracks all right?
- Help me!
- I'm doing it,
I'm doing the best I can.
- [Joel] We gotta get
organized, people,
we're not getting anywhere.
- [Crow] That'll happen.
♪ It's the end of the
world as we know it ♪
♪ And I feel fine ♪
- [Joel] Rock defeated clay.
- [Tom] Really
cracked up, didn't he?
(screaming)
- Gee, I hope she's okay.
- [Tom] I don't think so.
- [Joel] Things fall apart.
- [Tom] Yes, the best
lack all conviction,
while the worst are filled
with a passionate intensity.
Know what I mean?
- [Crow] Well, if it means
it's the end of the movie
I'm all for it.
- Okay.
Well.
Michael Gross, no!
- [Crow] When Atlantis
fell, Allstate was there.
- [Joel] We're raising
our building and
lowering our prices.
♪ Armageddon married
in the morning ♪
(laughing)
- That was wide open.
(screaming)
- Not the outhouse!
- Oh!
(vocalizing)
- [Crow] Man, if this
was in sound surround
it would be so cool!
- [Joel] Now that the
mountains have finally
tumbled into the
sea, a lot of people
have to stop loving
a lot of people.
- [Tom] We now return to
Force 10 from Navarone.
Well.
- Hmm.
- [Joel] Hmm.
(crying)
- [Tom] Oh, quit crying,
we've got problems too.
- [Joel] Crap, I didn't
know it would be that bad.
(murmuring)
(groaning)
- [Androcles] Hercules!
- [Crow] Tell me what happened
after you threw
that throne at me.
- What's going on, what ship
is this, where are we bound?
- I--
- Don't you remember anything?
- There was a shipwreck.
- Pull my finger.
- I fell overboard.
- Pull my thumb.
- I called your name.
There was a bright
light shining.
I don't remember any more.
- So then you don't
know what you did?
- What?
- What happened?
- What did I do?
- Ah, forget it,
it's really not worth it.
- You saved all of Greece.
- You big dope!
(laughing)
- [Tom] Oh come on, if
you really love me...
- [Joel] Oh I promise
I'll write ya,
I'll see you in September.
- [Crow] Come back to Atlantis.
- [Joel] Make it
Atlantis again, man.
- [Tom] Now let's listen
while Hercules recounts
the tale one more time.
- [Crow] Ah.
- [Joel] Hercules will be back
in Welcome Home, Roxy Hercules.
(vocalizing)
- [Tom] Spa, spa!
- Down boy, down!
- Let's go, let's go.
- Woo!
- Now that's done,
no more until they, no!
- What?
(adventurous music)
(doors whooshing)
And now the time is near,
the time to face the
final Hercules movie ever.
Forever and ever.
And if anyone here
knows of any reason why
this or any other Hercules movie
should not be laid to its
eternal resting place,
speak now or forever
hold your peace.
- Joel, I'd like to offer
a few words at this time,
if I may.
(clearing throat)
Friends, I feel as though I
were an intimate acquaintance
of Hercules and
each of his movies
and I think I speak for
Crow T. Robot, Joel Robinson
and Gypsy when I say, Herc,
wherever you are out there
in the mythological
kingdom, bite me!
- Well said, Servo, I
would just like to say that
although Herc was dumber
than a bag of hammers,
his pecs were really weird
lookin' and boy was he greasy.
And as I say goodbye I
also say I'm gonna party
like it's 1999, woo!
(cheering)
- We bested the tank!
- We made it through the rain!
- It's a wrap!
- Richard Basehart!
- Sir, Gypsy knew
Richard Basehart,
Richard Basehart was
a friend of hers.
Sir, you are no
Richard Basehart!
(laughing)
(cheering)
- Farewell,
alvederzane, goodbye!
- That's all, folks!
- Far out!
- Literally!
- Now let's take a
minute to read a letter
from one of our friends
in the Information Club.
- Cool.
- Let's put this up on
still store, Cambot.
Okay, it's from Teresa
Randon, here's this.
It's from Teresa Randon.
- Wow.
- And she writes, "I'm
writing this letter
"to tell you guys that I
really enjoy your show.
"Who am I trying to fool?
"I'm so nervous that y'all
might actually read this letter
"that I can't think
of anything to say.
"Of course I know my
letter doesn't contain
"humorous tidbits or artistic
renderings of MST3K stars
"and this means it won't
be read on the air.
"Humbly yours, Teresa Randon."
- Well, you're right,
Teresa, your letter
won't be read on the air, oh
I'm just kidding of course.
(laughing)
What do you think, sirs?
(yelling)
- Looks like I've got
some raking to do.
(somber music)
- Hercules!